The topic today is how to interpret tire ratings.
This tire is a two o five sixty slash sixteen.
And there's an R there.
The R means radial.
Other tires were bias.
There is a number here which is the temperature rating, four hundred.
There is a traction rating of AA and there's a temperature rating of A.
These numbers determine how long the tire will last and what type of speed they will take and how hard a tire they are.
There is also a number down here, which tells you the date the tire was made.
This one I think was thirty eight o six.
Which means it was made in a thirty eighth week of 06.
Sometimes when you buy tires, you'll find that they have been sitting on a shelf for a while.
Always check that rating first.
Tires should not be put in your car if they are more then five years old.
This will help you not to have a blowout or something.
Tires, although tires are brand new on the shelf, that doesn't mean that they haven't disintegrated.
The rubber deteriorates, everything deteriorates in a tire from the day they are manufactured.
So always check your temperatures, make sure you get the proper car tire for your car, this will determine how good your tire is.
And if it's the right tire and the right proper tire for your car.